Advanced natural language processing techniques are
人们已经在使用高阶自然语言处理技巧
being used to enhance fundamental analysis.
改进基本面分析结果
Fundamental analysis is the kind of work done by
基本面分析是传统投资分析师的工作
traditional investment analysts who work for financial institutions,
这些分析师任职于金融机构
like mutual funds and brokerage firms.
例如共同基金和经纪行
Much of the text-based analysis that fundamental researchers perform on companies,
基本面研究人员会对公司展开各种文本类分析
whether it's reading financial news,
例如阅读财经新闻
reading quarterly earnings reports,
阅读季度收益报告
listening to earnings calls,
接听盈收电话
or reading forms submitted to regulatory agencies,
或阅读提交至监管机构的报表
this work can be enhanced with natural language processing.
很多此类工作可以用自然语言处理技能增强
For example, a human analyst usually tracks 10 to 20 companies.
例如 人工分析师通常会跟踪 10 到 20 家公司
Computers could act as a first-pass filter
计算机可以第一遍过滤数据
sifting through the same data source for thousands of companies.
浏览数千家公司的同一数据源
The automated methods could filter,
自动化方法可以过滤
categorize, and label the information.
分类和标记信息
This could help fundamental analysts decide which companies or
这样有助于基本面分析师决定
information sources to prioritize for further analysis.
优先进一步分析哪些公司或信息来源
So, the pre-processing performed with NLP could support and
NLP 预处理可以支持和增强
enhance the existing workflow of fundamental research analysts.
基本面分析师的现有工作流程
One can also look for insights in
分析师还可以阅读
the required paperwork that companies send to government regulators.
公司提交给政府监管机构的报告并获得见解
In the United States,
在美国
the Securities Exchange Commission or SEC receives
公司每年向证券交易委员会 (SEC)
10-K forms from companies once a year and three 10-Q forms per year.
提交一份 10-K 报表并提交三份 10-Q 报表
The 10-K details the companies view of its business,
10-K 详细描述了公司对其业务
its past financial results for the year,
过去一年的财务业绩
as well as its current or potential future business risks.
以及当前或潜在未来业务风险的见解
One potential use of these 10-Ks is to track how a company's business evolves over time.
分析师可以根据这些 10-K 报表分析公司的业务多年来是如何发展的
For instance, one study used natural language processing to analyze
例如 有一项研究利用自然语言处理
Amazon's 10-Ks from the years 2007 to 2016.
分析了亚马逊从 2007 年到 2016 年的 10-K 报表
The researchers attempted to determine which sectors
研究人员想要根据 10-K 报表判断
the company most closely resembled based on its 10-K reports.
亚马逊与哪些行业最相似
In 2007, the company's description of
在 2007 年 亚马逊描述其业务
its business most resembled the software and hardware sectors.
最像软件和硬件行业
Over time, the company's description based on it's 10-K forms resembled more
后来 亚马逊根据 10-K 报表描述其业务
of the retail and software sector and to some extent the media sector.
更像零售和软件行业 并且在一定程度上像媒体行业
You may be wondering how we could make use of this information.
你可能会疑问 如何利用这一信息
The sector that companies closely resemble are
公司很接近的行业是一种因子
factors that help explain the price movement of their stocks.
可以解释公司的股价变化
You could imagine that retail stocks may be correlated to some extent,
可以想象 零售股可能比较相关
and technology companies may also exhibit similar price movements.
科技公司可能也会展现出相似的价格变化
In a later lesson,
在后面的课程中
we'll learn how the sector is a particularly important factor
我们将了解为何行业是很重要的因子
and we'll learn about adjusting a portfolio to be sector neutral.
并且将学习如何调整投资组合 使其保持行业中性
Another application of natural language processing on 10-K forms is sentiment analysis.
对 10-K 报表进行自然语言处理的另一个应用是情感分析
You may be familiar with sentiment analysis on movie reviews or restaurant reviews,
你可能熟悉影评或餐厅评价的情感分析
usually to categorize user-generated text as positive, neutral, or negative.
通常将用户生成的文本分类为正面 中立或负面
Sentiment analysis can be used with other categories as well.
情感分析还可以用于其他类别
For instance, one could apply sentiment analysis
例如 我们可以使用情感分析
to estimate how much little risk a company's 10-K
估测公司的 10-K 报表描述的法律风险是多少
describes or how much uncertainty
或者公司面临的
the company faces from competitors, customers, or suppliers.
竞争者 客户或供应商不确定性是多少
One could imagine creating factors based on positive outlook,
我们可以根据正面前景
negative outlook, little risk,
负面前景 法律风险
business uncertainty, or any number of categories.
业务不确定性或任何类别创建因子
These labels could also be used to create Alpha factors.
还可以使用这些标签创建 Alpha 因子
In fact, you will be applying natural language processing
实际上 你将在第二学期
on corporate documents in term two of this program.
对企业文档应用自然语言处理
For now, we want to first build-up
暂时 我们希望你首先对
a comfortable foundation in factor risk modeling and Alpha factor research.
因子风险建模和 Alpha 因子研究有基本的了解
This will give you the context to understand where
这样有助于你了解应该将 NLP 和深度学习技巧
NLP and deep learning techniques can fit into the quad workflow.
放在量化分析师工作流程的哪个环节